newtonrunning.com 2016-11-24

# Privacy/Terms

Newton Running Company ("Newton" or "we") operates this Site. This Privacy Policy is intended to inform you of our policies and practices regarding the collection, use and disclosure of any personal information you submit to us through our Site. "Personal Information" is information about you that is personally identifiable, like your name, address, email address or phone number, as well as other non-public information that is associated with the foregoing. "Anonymous Information" means information that is not associated with or linked to your Personal Information; Anonymous Information does not permit the identification of individual persons.

## USER CONSENT

By accessing or otherwise using our Site, you agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy and you expressly consent to the processing of your Personal Information according to this Privacy Policy.

Your Personal Information may be processed by Newton in the country where it was collected as well as other countries (including the United States) where laws regarding processing of Personal Information may be less stringent than the laws in your country.

## COLLECTION OF PERSONAL INFORMATION

We collect Personal Information that you submit to us voluntarily through our Site. The types of Personal Information we may collect are:

  * Names
  * Email address
  * Login information
  * Addresses
  * Phone numbers
  * Email subscription status
  * Order details (excluding credit card information)
  * Order history
  * Shipping details
  * Cookie settings ("remember me")
  * IP addresses

If you send an email to Newton, or fill out our "Contact Us" form on the Site, we will collect your email address and the full content of your email, including attached files, and other information you provide.

For all visitors: As you navigate our Site, certain information will also be passively collected, including Internet Protocol Addresses, Cookies and other navigational data. This type of information will be used for the purposes of gathering data to improve our Site, and to improve the quality of your experience when interacting with our Site.

An "Internet Protocol Address" or "IP Address" is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer when you use the Internet. In some cases your IP Address stays the same from browser session to browser session, but if you use a consumer Internet access provider, your IP Address probably varies from session to session. We track IP Addresses solely in conjunction with session cookies to analyze our web page flow. For instance, we use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server, and to administer our Site. Additionally, your IP address may be used to gather broad demographic information (e.g., number of users from Mexico).

"Cookies" are small pieces of information that a web site sends to your computer's hard drive while you are viewing a web site. Newton may use both session Cookies (which expire once you close your web browser) and persistent Cookies (which stay on your computer until you delete them) to provide you with a more personal and interactive experience on the Site. Persistent Cookies can be removed by following Internet browser help file directions. We use Cookies to simplify the login process (e.g., if you want Newton to “remember” you, so that you don't need to sign in the next time you visit the site). In order to use the Newton services offered through the Site, your web browser must accept Cookies. If you choose to disable Cookies, some areas of the Site may not work properly, and you will not be able to receive Newton services.

## USE OF PERSONAL INFORMATION

In general, Personal Information you provide to us is used to respond to requests that you make or to provide you Newton services.

We may create Anonymous Information records from Personal Information by excluding information (such as your name) that make the information personally identifiable to you. We may use this Anonymous Information to analyze usage patterns and for statistical purposes. Newton reserves the right to use and disclose Anonymous Information to third parties at its discretion.

## DISCLOSURE OF PERSONAL INFORMATION

We may share some or all of your Personal Information with our Affiliates (i.e., our parent company, any of its subsidiaries, joint ventures or other companies under a common control), in which case we will require our Affiliates to honor this Privacy Policy. If our company or our assets are acquired by another company, that company will possess the Personal Information collected by us and it will assume the rights and obligations regarding your Personal Information as described in this Privacy Policy.

We may use third parties to facilitate or outsource one or more aspects of the services that we provide to you and therefore we may provide some Personal Information directly to these service providers. These service providers are subject to confidentiality agreements with us that prohibit their use or disclosure of the information we provide them for any purpose other than to facilitate the specific outsourced service.

We may disclose your Personal Information if we believe in good faith that such disclosure is necessary to (a) comply with relevant laws or to respond to subpoenas or warrants served on Newton, or (b) protect and defend the rights or property of Newton or users of our Site.

## YOUR CHOICES REGARDING YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION

We offer you choices regarding the collection, use and sharing of your Personal Information. When you receive newsletters or promotional communications from us, you may indicate a preference to stop receiving further communications from us and you will have the opportunity to "opt out." You may unsubscribe by following an "Unsubscribe" link provided in the footer of each email message from Newton. If you unsubscribe, your address will no longer be listed in the publisher-accessible mailing list.

Despite your indicated email preferences, we may send you administrative emails regarding our products or notices of any updates to our Privacy Policy.

## REGARDING CHILDREN

Our Site is not designed for children under the age of 13. We do not intentionally gather Personal Information about visitors in this age group.

## LINKS TO OTHER SITES

Our provision of a link to any other website or location is for your convenience and does not signify our endorsement of such other website or location or its contents. We have no control over, do not review, and cannot be responsible for, these outside websites or their content. Please be aware that the terms of our Privacy Policy do not apply to these outside websites.

## SECURITY

We use a variety of industry-standard security technologies and procedures to help protect your Personal Information from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. Your Personal Information is contained behind secure networks and is only accessible to a limited number of persons who have special access rights to such systems, and are required to keep the information confidential. When you place orders or access your Personal Information, we offer the use of a secure server. Credit card numbers allow a user to subscribe to (and thus pay for) our business service. All credit card information you supply is transmitted via Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology and then encrypted into our databases to be accessed only as stated above. We will use the information for purposes of processing and completing only those transactions you approve, and the information will be disclosed to third parties only as necessary to complete a specific transaction. However, no company, including Newton, can fully eliminate security risks associated with Personal Information.

## REVIEWING AND REVISING PERSONAL INFORMATION

Our Site provides users the opportunity to opt out of receiving communications from us at the point where we request information about the user and whenever we send information to the user that they've requested. The Site gives you options for removing your information from our database to not receive future communications or to no longer receive our service. In order to remove your information from our database, please contact customer service via telephone or email.

To change and modify information previously provided, registered users may visit their Manage My Account page and change their contact information for email and instant messaging notifications from Newton.

## SUBMISSION OF UNSOLICITED MATERIALS

Unfortunately, we are unable to consider unsolicited proposals submitted to us. We consider any comments or materials you submit to us, including questions, technical or creative suggestions or ideas, to be non-confidential and non-proprietary. Newton has no obligation of any kind with respect to any such submissions.

By submitting any content, materials, advice, feedback or any other information (collectively "Content") to Newton Running Company, you unconditionally grant to Newton Running Company a non-exclusive, perpetual, irrevocable, worldwide, fully-paid, transferable, right and license, with the right to sub-license through multiple levels of sub-licensees, under all of your intellectual property rights in the Content, to (a) reproduce, create derivative works of, distribute, publicly perform, publicly display, digitally transmit, and otherwise use the Content in any medium or format, whether now known or hereafter discovered and (b) exercise any and all other present or future rights in the Content.

## CONTACT US

Should you have any questions or concerns regarding this Privacy Policy, please contact us:

Newton Running Company  
1300 Walnut St., Suite 100  
Boulder, CO 80302  
(877) 860-7695  

## PRIVACY POLICY UPDATES

This Privacy Policy is subject to occasional revision, and if we make any substantial changes in the way we use your Personal Information, we will post an alert on this page. If you object to any such changes, you must cease using our Site. Continued use of our Site following notice of any such changes shall indicate your acknowledgment of such changes and agreement to be bound by the terms and conditions of such changes.

Last Updated May 2012

For all visitors: As you navigate our Site, certain information will also be passively collected, including Internet Protocol Addresses, Cookies and other navigational data. This type of information will be used for the purposes of gathering data to improve our Site, and to improve the quality of your experience when interacting with our Site.
